[KARA] This is the point of life.
Watching the sun rise…
…with the person you love.
I love you, Jao.
No matter what happens,
always remember,
as long as the waves find their way back to shore,
I’ll always love you.
- [PEARL] Oh! Good day, sir! - Hello.
- Checking in? - Yes.
[PEARL] Well, welcome to Katig, sir.
Let me guess... Korean.
The owner of this hotel, my boss, he’s Korean, too.
[GUEST] Where is he?
[HAN BIN SPEAKS KOREAN] Stop it already.
The guy you sent is trying to take me back!
Sir Han.
We have a Korean guest and he wants to meet you.
What’s happening?
There’s a lot of things I need to tell you, but...
I never found the right opportunity.
I like you, Pearl.
A lot.
Wait, you’re confessing, but why does it feel like you’re—
[PEARL BREATHES DEEPLY]
you’re saying goodbye?
I won’t say goodbye.
[HAN BIN] I’ll see you again.
So? Does he have a chance with you?
[TANTAN] Hey, Pearl. I drove Sir Han earlier today.
To where?
To the airport. T​​hey’re flying back to Korea.
- [ARIEL] Huh? - Airport?
Sorry, Pearl.
Sir Han really is confusing.
He doesn't owe me an explanation.
So, it’s okay.
- [ARIEL] But don’t you think— - It’s okay, Ariel.
See you, Tantan.
Pearl doesn't seem okay.
Tantan, she’s fine. Don’t worry.
Join us tomorrow at Cabitoonan, okay?
- We're planting mangroves. - Sure.
- See you! - Sir Handsome invited me, too.
Okay!
- See you there! - See you!
[ARIEL SPEAKS SIARGAONON] Good morning, Sir Noah!
[ARIEL SPEAKS SIARGAONON] Good morning! Say hi to my vlog!
Good morning to all our viewers!
We're here today at Barangay Cabitoonan
for the first day of our planting ceremony
for our mangrove reserve extension.
All right.
Follow Pure Coast on social media!
Pure Coast is here.
Thank you, Pure Coast!
Say hi to the vlog!
Thank you, Pure Coast! Hello!
[SIARGAONON] Over here!
[ARIEL] How are you guys doing?
Too bad Sir Han isn’t here.
I wonder how his family is doing?
- [CAROL LAUGHS] - Princess Pearl sure misses him.
Oh, Princess Pearl.
All right! Let’s get planting! Time to focus!
Let’s go! One, two, three! Let's start planting!
- [CAROL] Let’s go! - [CROWD CHEERING]
Let’s do the mangroves!
Yes! Because mangroves fight the letter B!
- B! - Bailing on us!
- Wrong answer! - It’s wrong?
Bad weather or floods! Not boys!
- Oh, Princess Pearl… - [ARIEL] Right.
- ...you’re in love. Right, Tantan? - Of course, Chona Mae.
Oh! Right? Who’s Chona Mae?
- [ARIEL] Chona Mae? - [YELPS] Who’s Chona Mae?
- [ARIEL LAUGHS] - Oh! Jeez.
[ARIEL] You don’t know Chona Mae, Mom?
- Uh... That’s Chona Mae. - Wrong.
Chona Mae, as in tsunami! Come on!
- [PEARL LAUGHS] Mom! - What kind of joke is that?
- You don’t know what a tsunami is? - Fine.
- [ARIEL] Mom, your age is showing. - Right, it’s a tsunami!
I’m getting tsunami’d here in the mangroves.
- [PEARL LAUGHS] - There! We can do this!
As long as we stick together here in the mangroves!
[ALON BY JL]
"Such beautiful mangroves. Such a beautiful sight."
Say hi to my vlog, Kara, Jao!
What’s up, vlog?
Egay, say hi!
[BACKGROUND CHATTER]
[JAO] Uh...
You know, Kara, you should plant the first mangrove...
because this project won't be possible without you.
Why me? This is everyone's project.
- [JAO] Come on. - [ARIEL] Kara, actually...
[ARIEL] it's better if we show someone planting first.
It will look better on video.
And it will raise awareness.
Let Egay do it. Egay.
- [JAO] Okay. - Go ahead and plant first.
[EGAY] Why me?
Because what we’re doing here today is for you.
For the children of Siargao.
Go on, start planting.
[KARA] Give your mangrove a name, too.
[JAO] Already have a name in mind?
Need help naming it?
How about Jao? So you'll always remember me.
How about Karajao? Like your baby.
[ARIEL] A baby already?
- [ARIEL] Egay! - [JAO LAUGHS]
[ARIEL] You’re getting way ahead of yourself.
Karajao actually sounds nice.
Karajao… baby.
[ARIEL] Hmm...
Jao is fine.
- Just Jao, right, Egay? - [JAO CHUCKLING]
[ARIEL] Okay, everybody, look at the camera, okay?
On three, everyone say: Team Mangroves forever!
One, two, three—
[CROWD] Team Mangroves forever!
[CROWD CHEERING]
[CROWD CHANTING] Team Mangroves!
[MAN] Let's go!
- [JAO] Use both hands. There you go. - [KARA] There.
- [ARIEL] There you go. - [JAO] Push it down first.
Then use this to…
[ARIEL] Kara, how are we going to plant all of these?
There's still so many!
[JAO] Oh!
Tomorrow, some student volunteers from San Isidro are coming.
And you didn’t tell me?
I wanted it to be a surprise.
Thanks. It really means a lot.
To… to everyone!
- To everyone? - The community...
the people of Cabitoonan... - [JAO] Oh.
- To Mother Earth... - To you...?
- Thank you. - To you, too?
- [ARIEL] Way to involve Mother Earth. - Come on, let's start planting!
[ARIEL] Okay. Let’s plant!
[ARIEL] KaraJao.
Song Ji Hoon.
Is this Sir Han?
Chaebol…?
What’s that?
[KARA] Don't think about Han Bin too much, he might bite his tongue.
I'm just researching mangroves.
[CAROL LAUGHS]
[ARIEL] So, tell me, what’s the scientific name of mangroves?
Who did this?
[JAO] Kara!
- [JAO] Where are you going? - [KARA] The municipal office!
[CAROL] What a shame.
Ma’am Vida!
[VIDA] Kara, I was just about to call you.
I heard what happened.
Ma'am Vida, what happened?
Didn't your office already approve our project?
We have a permit!
I know. And the permit is valid.
But we got a call from the new landowner.
New owner?
But there isn't any land left there, right?
The sea took it.
Didn’t we make it clear to your group?
The land where you want to plant mangroves
was once private property affected by sea level rise.
Therefore, it’s public domain now, right?
It belongs to the government!
Yes, but under the law,
the previous owner still has priority
if they want to apply for an FLA.
Foreshore Lease Agreement?
Yes, it's the agreement that lets you use land along the shore.
You just lease it from the government.
Why? Is there a development planned?
What are they building?
I can't give you that information because I don't know either.
Ms. Vida, please.
I know the previous landowner.
But they’re not the ones we’re dealing with.
We found out that
before the sea swallowed the land,
it had already been sold to a corporation.
I know how this will play out.
[JAO] I’ve seen this before.
For now, we need to find out
who the previous owner sold the property to.
Maybe, uh...
we can start there and offer them some alternatives.
Maybe the mayor can help us.
Noah said...
Pure Coast told him developers rarely give in to such mediations.
- [KARA SIGHS] - [JAO] We know there's a development,
but we don't know how big it will be.
I mean, let’s face it.
Siargao is prime real estate for big developments now.
And that property is huge!
So a big hotel will definitely be built there.
It’s really disturbing how
these people see paradise and only think of profit.
They will destroy mangroves,
overbuild coastlines,
drain resources… And what?
Call it progress? Because they're making money?
When the ecosystem gets destroyed,
they won't be the ones who’ll suffer the consequences!
I'm sorry, okay? I don't mean to offend you.
And I don't mean to generalize...
- But surely there are some— - Wait. Kara.
You don’t have to apologize.
I understand you.
And your objections are valid.
[JAO SIGHS]
It's just that...
I can already hear my boss's voice in my head, saying...
that everything is legal and aboveboard.
That this project will provide revenue for the local government
and jobs for the people.
Just because it’s permitted doesn’t mean it’s right.
Yes, it will provide jobs.
Temporarily.
At the end of the day, who'll suffer the consequences?
The next generation.
And some ecosystems may not recover once they're damaged.
Don’t worry.
I’m with you in this fight.
And I will fulfill my promise to Ruth…
and to you.
It's nice to have someone fighting by my side.
[PHONE VIBRATING]
Let it be.
[PHONE CONTINUES VIBRATING]
[ARIEL] So...
[ARIEL SPEAKS SIARGAONON] Han Bin oppa's real name is Song Ji Hoon!
- Song Ji Hoon? Song Ji Hoon. - Song Ji Hoon.
[ARIEL SPEAKS SIARGAONON] No wonder he didn't like taking pictures
or videos with us.
Was he hiding from his family?
[SIARGAONON] For sure!
Because he's a chaebol, right?
He's the heir to his family's business.
But...
Isn't Han Bin oppa...
a free spirit?
He loves traveling and experiencing cultures.
He wants to be free.
We've known him for so long now, right?
[SIARGAONON] That's right.
And he never even trusted us enough to tell us the truth?
If his father hadn't gotten sick,
or if he hadn't left, we would have never known, right?
[ARIEL] Because he was hiding from his family.
Whatever his reason,
it's probably for the best that he didn't burden us
- with hiding his identity. - [CAROL] That’s right!
Whatever Han Bin oppa’s reason was,
I'm just glad he chose to be treated like one of us!
[ARIEL] Yeah.
We got to see the real him.
- [SIARGAONON] That's right. - [CAROL] Hm.
[PEARL SIGHS]
Hm...
Pearl.
[SIARGAONON] How are you?
[CAROL] Pearl!
Hm?
[SIARGAONON] Are you okay?
You miss him?
[ARIEL AND CAROL SQUEALING]
Hm?
[PEARL SIGHS]
I just want to know how he's doing, Mom.
[CAROL] Hm.
He seems to be going through something serious.
He hasn't even replied to my messages!
Princess Pearl, he'll reply!
Yeah.
You know there's a family emergency.
Right.
Pearl, just like what Kara said,
[SIARGAONON] "He'll come back to Siargao."
You'll get to talk again.
[SIARGAONON] Yeah. That's right.
Mhmm...
Hm...
- Hm... - Hm...
Here.
[CAROL CHUCKLES]
[CAROL SIGHS]
[BROOM SWEEPING]
[NOAH] Looks like we won't get to see the mayor.
No. He'll talk to us.
Ma'am Vida said he's just busy.
Let's just wait.
[NOAH] You know, I really admire your resilience.
We have to keep fighting.
Yup. It's exhausting.
But I think every fight helps us defend the environment better.
[STAFF] Kara, Noah. I'm sorry.
The mayor can’t meet with you today due to an emergency meeting.
But come back tomorrow.
Promise, I'll prioritize you guys.
[KARA] Okay. We’ll be here during flag ceremony.
- [STAFF] Okay. Sure. - Thank you.
- [STAFF] Thanks. I’ll go to my meeting now. - Okay.
Kara, look at this.
Is there something you want to tell me?
How could you be the project head?
Were you even going to tell me?
But can you please trust me on this?
How can I trust you right now?
Do you hear yourself?
‘Cause right now, you sound exactly like your boss.
[CAROL] Without those mangroves,
the storm would have hit the island even harder.
[KARA] So please, come with me tomorrow.
[KARA] Just think about it. Those trees aren't just trees.
They're protecting our community.
And they're our legacy for the next generation.
[CAROL] Jao!
This project can’t move forward, Jao.
Thanks to your company.
I’m just being rational and professional about this.
[PAUL] Kara, right?
I’m Paul. Jao’s boss.
10 million. Name your price.